<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hideyuki Kawashima | Masafumi Oyamada</title>
    <link>https://mooz.github.io/authors/hideyuki-kawashima/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://mooz.github.io/authors/hideyuki-kawashima/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Hideyuki Kawashima</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://mooz.github.io/images/icon_hud76b0b5cb03cbdbd01ad5fbc1aeef883_89416_512x512_fill_linear_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Hideyuki Kawashima</title>
      <link>https://mooz.github.io/authors/hideyuki-kawashima/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Stream Processing with Concurrency Control</title>
      <link>https://mooz.github.io/publication/acr2013-transactional-stream/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mooz.github.io/publication/acr2013-transactional-stream/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Continuous Query Processing with Concurrency Control: Reading Updatable Resources Consistently</title>
      <link>https://mooz.github.io/publication/sac2013-transactional-stream/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mooz.github.io/publication/sac2013-transactional-stream/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A recent trend in data stream processing shows the use of advanced continuous
queries (CQs) that reference non-streaming resources such as relational data in
databases and machine learning models. Since non-streaming resources could be
shared among multiple systems, resources may be updated by the systems during
the CQ execution. As a consequence, CQs may reference resources inconsistently,
and lead to a wide range of problems from inappropriate results to fatal system
failures. We address this inconsistency problem by introducing the concept of
transaction processing onto data stream processing. We introduce CQ-derived
transaction, a concept that derives read-only transactions from CQs, and
illustrate that the inconsistency problem is solved by ensuring serializability
of derived transactions and resource updating transactions. To ensure
serializability, we propose three CQ-processing strategies based on concurrency
control techniques: two-phase lock strategy, snapshot strategy, and optimistic
strategy. Experimental study shows our CQ-processing strategies guarantee proper
results, and their performances are comparable to the performance of
conventional strategy that could produce improper results.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Efficient Invocation of Transaction Sequences Triggered by Data Streams</title>
      <link>https://mooz.github.io/publication/3pgcic2011-sequential-transaction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mooz.github.io/publication/3pgcic2011-sequential-transaction/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
