<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Shinji Nakadai | Masafumi Oyamada</title>
    <link>https://mooz.github.io/ja/authors/shinji-nakadai/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://mooz.github.io/ja/authors/shinji-nakadai/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Shinji Nakadai</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>ja</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://mooz.github.io/images/icon_hud76b0b5cb03cbdbd01ad5fbc1aeef883_89416_512x512_fill_linear_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Shinji Nakadai</title>
      <link>https://mooz.github.io/ja/authors/shinji-nakadai/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meimei: An Efficient Probabilistic Approach for Semantically Annotating Tables</title>
      <link>https://mooz.github.io/ja/publication/aaai2019-meimei/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mooz.github.io/ja/publication/aaai2019-meimei/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Given a large amount of table data, how can we find the tables that contain the
contents we want? A naive search fails when the column names are ambiguous, such
as if columns containing stock price information are named “Close” in one table
and named “P” in another table.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One way of dealing with this problem that has been gaining attention is the
semantic annotation of table data columns by using canonical knowledge. While
previous studies successfully dealt with this problem for specific types of
table data such as web tables, it still remains for various other types of table
data: (1) most approaches do not handle table data with numerical values, and
(2) their predictive performance is not satisfactory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This paper presents a novel approach for table data annotation that combines a
latent probabilistic model with multilabel classifiers. It features three
advantages over previous approaches due to using highly predictive multi-label
classifiers in the probabilistic computation of semantic annotation. (1) It is
more versatile due to using multi-label classifiers in the probabilistic model,
which enables various types of data such as numerical values to be supported.
(2) It is more accurate due to the multi-label classifiers and probabilistic
model working together to improve predictive performance. (3) It is more
efficient due to potential functions based on multi-label classifiers reducing
the computational cost for annotation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Extensive experiments demonstrated the superiority of the proposed approach over
state-of-the-art approaches for semantic annotation of real data (183
human-annotated tables obtained from the UCI Machine Learning Repository).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Relational Mixture of Experts: Explainable Demographics Prediction with Behavioral Data</title>
      <link>https://mooz.github.io/ja/publication/icdm2017-relational-mixture-of-experts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mooz.github.io/ja/publication/icdm2017-relational-mixture-of-experts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Given a collection of basic customer demographics (e.g., age and gender) and
their behavioral data (e.g., item purchase histories), how can we predict
sensitive demographics (e.g., income and occupation) that not every customer
makes available? This demographics prediction problem is modeled as a
classification task in which a customer&amp;rsquo;s sensitive demographic y is predicted
from his feature vector x.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far, two lines of work have tried to produce a &amp;ldquo;good&amp;rdquo; feature vector x from
the customer&amp;rsquo;s behavioral data: (1) application-specific feature engineering
using behavioral data and (2) representation learning (such as singular value
decomposition or neuralembedding) on behavioral data. Although these approaches
successfully improve the predictive performance, (1) designing a good feature
requires domain experts to make a great effort and (2) features obtained from
representation learning are hard to interpret.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To overcome these problems, we present a Relational Infinite Support Vector
Machine (R-iSVM), a mixture-of-experts model that can leverage behavioral data.
Instead of augmenting the feature vectors of customers, R-iSVM uses behavioral
data to find out behaviorally similar customerclusters and constructs a local
prediction model at each customer cluster. In doing so, R-iSVM successfully
improves the predictive performance withoutrequiring application-specific
feature designing and hard-to-interpret representations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Experimental results on three real-world datasets demonstrate the predictive
performance and interpretability of R-iSVM. Furthermore, R-iSVM can co-exist
with previous demographics prediction methods to further improve their
predictive performance.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Link Prediction for Isolated Nodes in Heterogeneous Network by Topic-Based Co-clustering</title>
      <link>https://mooz.github.io/ja/publication/pakdd2017-topic-bi-clustering/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mooz.github.io/ja/publication/pakdd2017-topic-bi-clustering/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This paper presents a new probabilistic generative model (PGM) that predicts
links for isolated nodes in a heterogeneous network using textual data. In
conventional PGMs, a link between two nodes is predicted on the basis of the
nodes’ other existing links. This method makes it difficult to predict links for
isolated nodes, which happens when new items are recommended. In this study, we
first naturally expand the relational topic model (RTM) to a heterogeneous
network (Hetero-RTM). However, this simple extension degrades performance in a
link prediction for existing nodes. We present a new model called the Grouped
Hetero-RTM that has both latent topics and latent clusterings. Through intensive
experiments that simulate real recommendation problems, the Grouped Hetero-RTM
outperforms baseline methods at predicting links for isolated nodes. This model,
furthermore, performs as effectively as the stochastic block model in the link
prediction for existing nodes. We also find that the Grouped Hetero-RTM is
effective for various textual data such as item reviews and movie descriptions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
